now let's discuss the solution for the
active power quiz what we had was that
to achieve some frequency we needed to
increase voltage beyond some point and
we knew that at 1 volt and 2 gigahertz
the power was 30 watts so the question
is what is the power for the most power
efficient setting
and what is the power for the highest
performance setting the most power
efficient setting will be the one with
the lowest frequency and the lowest
voltage why
because the power if you remember is
equal to
something
times voltage square times frequency so
we need to have to reduce power we need
to both lower the frequency and reduce
voltage so most power efficiency i think
is this one relative to this setting the
power for the most efficient setting is
going to be equal to so this stands for
efficient power it's going to be 30
watts
times the voltage is now 0.9
of what it was so it's 0.9
squared times
the frequency now is 1.8 over 2 so this
is again 0.9 of what it was and when we
multiply this out we get
21.9 watts
or 22 watts so the answer here is that
the power is 21.9 watts
now let's do the same but this time for
the highest performance setting the
highest performance setting is the one
that gives us the highest frequency what
we have now is the power for the
performance is going to be equal to 30
watts times the voltage is now 1.5 times
what it was so it's 1.5 square
times
the frequency is 3 instead of 2
gigahertz so that has also increased by
a factor of 1.5 and if you multiply this
out we get 101.3 watts so as you can see
there is a huge difference between the
most power efficient and the highest
performance setting although in fact the
difference between these two settings is
not even a factor of two in performance
why well because power is not only
proportional to frequency it's also
proportional to voltage squared and
reducing the frequency allows us to
reduce the voltage